翻譯:Jamie 宛若安寧 Sumsmit
下一個輪到誰呢 蓋斯汽油車嗎
What's next in the toy pile? Hess gasoline truck.
- 去或留  - 不知道 喇叭還能響嗎
- Keep or chuck?  - I don't know. Does the horn work?
校對:不賣萌斯基
噢 留著吧
Oh, that's a keeper.
后期:LEO19
愛因斯坦搖頭娃娃
Albert Einstein bobble head.
噢 真難取舍 搖搖看
Ooh, that's a tough one. Give it a shake.
瞧我說什么呢
Wait, what am I saying?
壓制:B B
- 對不起了愛因斯坦  - 好吧
- Yeah. Sorry, Al.  - Yep.
- 丟了吧  - 噢 Fluffles先生
- Let's chuck it. - Oh! Mr. Fluffles!
還記得嗎 最開始是Ian的
You remember this? This used to be Ian's.
在Eve還小時 他把它送給了Eve
And then he gave it to Eve when she was a baby.
- 她還經常咬它  - 后來她給了Graham
- She used to chew on it.  - And then she gave it to Graham
因為這是"傳銃"（模仿小孩不清晰的發音）
because it was "Twadition."
他身上滿滿都是美好回憶
Lot of memories in this guy.
也滿是細菌 抱歉了 Fluffles
And a lot of germs. Sorry, Fluffles.
我覺得差不多了
Well, I think our work here is done.
這些都是我們買的嗎 他不應該更愛我們嗎
We bought him all this stuff? Shouldn't he love us more?
這些玩具他好多年沒碰了
He hasn't played with a lot of these toys in years.
不會發現這些東西不見了
He won't even notice anything's gone.
我的玩具呢
Where's my stuff?!
走走走 快跑 跑
Move, move, move! Go, go, go, go, go.
又 見 彩 虹
第一季  第九集
電波誠譯
穿了條紋運動褲嗎
Got your track pants on?
- 你怎么知道  - 在走廊就聽見你的動靜了
- How could you tell?  - I could hear you coming down the hall.
黑手黨為啥還穿這個 怎么去槍殺人
Why do mob guys wear these? How do you pull off a hit?
- 你們偷了我的玩具 為什么  - 我們沒偷 寶貝
- You stole my toys. Why?  - We didn't steal anything, honey?
我和你爸只是覺得應該把那些東西
Your dad and I just thought we'd give those things
- 送給更有需要的家庭  - 那些沒有
- to a few needy families.  - Who don't have disembodied
斷頭愛因斯坦的家庭
Albert Einstein heads of their own.
我還在你衣柜后面找到一個用膠帶綁著的
And I found one of your action figures wrapped in duct tape
裝在快餐袋里的玩具模型
in a fast food bag behind your dresser.
我留著有用的
I was saving it for something.
沒人用的東西我們就不留了
We can't keep things that nobody's gonna use.
- 懂嗎 寶貝  - 懂
- You understand, buddy?  - I do.
你穿的是條紋運動褲嗎 爸
Track pants? Really, Dad?
你知道嗎 我在<今日男士>
You know, if there's one thing I learned
學到了一點 就是今日你的穿著
working at today's man, it's that today's man
彰顯你明天想要什么工作
dresses for the job he wants tomorrow today.
也許我想當籃球運動員呢
What if I wanna be a basketball player?
學著點吧 爸 太太 這是你的先生嗎
Watch and learn, Dad. Miss, is this your husband?
搞什么 我不喜歡這樣
What is this? I hate this.
您是位風姿卓越的女性
You are a woman of exceptional beauty.
而他穿成這樣 你還覺得臉上有光嗎
When he dresses like this, do you feel taken care of?
- 您尊貴如女王  - 說實話 我覺得
- Like the queen that you are?  - Actually, I don't f...
- 好了 你這是在調戲我嗎  - 噓
- Okay, are you hitting on me?  - Shh.
- 把手伸到我口袋里去  - Ian
- Reach inside my pocket.  - Ian.
不 里面有張名片
No, there's a business card in there.
這是Arben教我的銷售技巧
It's a sales technique Arben taught me.
配上個口音效果更佳
It works better with an accent.
- 用在除了你媽的人身上也更佳  - 隨便啦 打給我
- And on somebody other than your mom.  - Either way, call me.
我給你穿上套這位女士想要剝掉的西服
I'll get you into a suit she'll wanna get you out of.
好嘞 我要去代班了
Gotta jam. I have to cover an extra shift.
Ranesh打開了一盒人造皮革皮帶后昏過去了
Ranesh passed out when he opened up a box of synthetic belts.
我很擔心他 你看 他輟學去開科技公司
I'm worried about him. I mean, he quit college to
而現在又干別的了
start a tech company and now he's not even doing that.
好了 賣衣服只是暫時的工作嘛
Well, the suit job's just a temporary thing.
你怎么知道他不是下一個Mark Zuckerberg
You never know, he could be the next Mark Zuckerberg.
Mark Zuckerberg  facebook創始人
Mark Zuckerberg會跟高中女生約會嗎
Did Mark Zuckerberg date a high school girl?
- 如果能的話他也會  - 我只是有些擔心
- He would've if he could've.  - I'm just worried
他無法發揮己長
he's not living up to his potential.
真想修理他一頓
I wanna just grab him and
然后把他綁起來扔回學校
tie him up and drag him back to college.
- 你做不到的  - 我知道 他比我大只
- You can't do that. - I know. He's bigger than me.
不過我能
I would have the element
- 乘其不備  - 至少穿這條褲子不行
- of surprise though.  - Not in those pants.
Mike 我們談過的 孩子們長大了
Mike, we've talked about this. Our kids are getting older.
我們再也不能強迫他們做什么了
We can't force 'em to do what we want to anymore.
看著 寶貝 今天過得怎么樣
Watch this. Hey, honey, how was your day?
你問我是不是希望十幾歲的女兒
Would I prefer my teenage
跟我說兩句而不是哼哼一聲嗎 當然
daughter speak to me instead of grunt? Sure.
可是從14歲開始 成人都是他們的敵人
But after they turn 14, adults are the enemy.
好吧 至少我們還可以擺布Graham
Well, at least we still have Graham to push around.
他生氣時特別可愛
It was so cute when he got all mad.
"噢 把我的東西還回來 我生氣了"
"Oh, you give me my stuff back. I'm so angry!"
我都沒見過他們用
I've never seen them use it.
不 很抱歉 我以為我們協商好了的
No, I'm sorry. I thought we had an agreement.
我看了價格 這利潤太不合理了
I've looked at the numbers and these margins are unacceptable.
什么 你以為我是第一次做交易嗎
What, do you think this is the first deal that I've ever made?
趕緊把這弄好 別耍滑頭
Make this right, slick.
聽到Ian在談生意
Hearing Ian on that phone call talking business,
我不得不承認 我很驚嘆
I gotta admit, I was impressed.
不屈不撓的談判啊
Tough negotiating.
真該讓你去和時代華納談談
I should get you on the phone with time warner.
時代華納 美國大型多媒體公司
謝謝老爸 真抱歉讓你聽到這些
Thanks, Dad. Ugh. Sorry you had to hear that.
只是當你租一部加長悍馬時
It's just, you expect a certain level of service
肯定希望相應水準的服務嘛
when you're renting a stretch hummer.
對啊 就是要  你說什么
Right, you have to... what?
是啊 他們企圖用輛派對小貨車來糊弄我
Yeah, they tried to bait and switch me into a party van.
我可不能用那輛送Reese去返校節
Can't take Reese to homecoming in that.
你要去高中舞會嗎
You're going to a high school dance?
要我坐派對貨車就不去了
Ha! Not in a party van I'm not.
這一定要安排得滴水不漏 返校節可是人生必經階段
No, this has to be perfect. Homecoming's a rite of passage.
是啊 這階段你都經了兩次了 你通過了
Yeah, a rite of passage you've been through twice. You passed.
聽著 Reese還沒去過舞會呢
Look, Reese has never been to a dance.
她想得到公主待遇
She wants to be treated like a princess.
雖然在你聽來有點愚蠢
I know that sounds stupid to you...
怎么 你在等我反駁你嗎
I'm sorry, are you waiting for me to disagree?
反正這對她很重要
Well, it's important to her.
公司同事幫我搞到一套晚禮服
And the guys at the shop got me a great deal on a tux
就在紐澤西分店的特賣場 都是工廠回收貨
at our outlet in Jersey. All factory recalls.
你知道"勿點燃"和"易燃"是一個意思嗎
Did you know inflammable means the same thing as flammable?
你租了套會著火的衣服嗎
You rented a suit that catches on fire?
沒有 爸 我又不是傻子 我買了
No, Dad, I'm not an idiot. I bought it.
返校節 畢業舞會 春季嘉年華
Homecoming, prom, the spring fling.
穿三次 物超所值
Three wears, the tux pays for itself.
還要想辦法怎么去紐澤西拿回來
Just need to figure out a way to get to New Jersey to pick it up.
Annie說得對 你不能強迫孩子做你想要的
Annie was right, you can't force your kids to do what you want.
可你總不能從開著的車上跳下來吧
But you also can't jump out of a moving car.
是時候來一次即興返校參觀了
It was time for an impromptu college tour.
- 我送你去  - 你不用去工作嗎
- I'll take you.  - Don't you have work?
最近正好有空閑 更何況 這可是返校節
I'm between assignments. Besides, this is homecoming.
你的人生第三次必經階段啊
It's a thrice in a lifetime event.
然后我就說"才不管他們在日本是怎么做的
And I said, "I don't care what they're doing in Japan.
把你舌頭從我眼球上拿開"
Keep your tongue away from my eyeball."
不錯嘛 你終于有點下限了
That's good. You're setting boundaries.
我現在十分在意戀愛初期階段的交流
I'm all about communicating early in a relationship now.
我才跟Eve說過要跟Jonah這樣
I was just telling Eve she has got to set that tone with Jonah.
等等 誰 誰是Jonah
Wait, who... who's Jonah?
就是在她發現Chris是同性戀后
You know, the guy she started seeing
開始交往的男朋友
after Chris turned out to be gay.
- Chris?  -  噢 是的
- Chris?  - Oh, yeah.
他真是個超完美的初戀男友
He was the perfect first boyfriend.
文質彬彬 熱愛跳舞
Not too handsy, loved to dance.
她什么時候告訴你的
So I... when did she tell you all this?
我們去買返校節衣服的時候
When we went shopping for homecoming dresses.
校友返校節衣服 不錯嘛 她的第一支舞
Oh, shopping for homecoming, that's nice. Her first dance.
我女兒和"你"的重要回憶
Something that my daughter and "You" Will never forget.
我讀了100本育兒寶典
I've read 100 parenting books and they all say
他們都說要給十幾歲的女兒空間
you're supposed to give your teenage daughter space.
很明顯這樣我狡猾的小姑就可以
Apparently so your weaselly sister-in-law
趁機而入偷走我的寶貴回憶
can slide in there and steal your memories.
那你們 有拍照留念嗎
Did you... did you take some pictures?
- 噢 沒有啊  - 好吧 畢業舞會記得拍
- Oh, we didn't.  - Well, you can always do that at prom.
- 你疊的衣服也太丑了吧  - 這叫創意
- You're a terrible folder.  - I'm creative.
- 折疊何曾有過創意  - 折紙手工
- When has folding ever been creative?  - Origami.
- 嘿  - 嘿 親愛的
- Hey.  - Hey, honey.
還記得你說過我無法
Remember when you said I
把我們兒子抓回大學嗎
couldn't just drag our son back to Cornell?
- 很明顯我快成功了  - 你沒有把他綁起來吧
- Turns out I can.  - You didn't tie him up, did you?
沒 根本用不著 他實在太好騙了
No, I didn't have to. He's wildly gullible.
- 這都歸功于你  - Mike 返校節怎么辦
- I put that on you, by the way. - Mike, what about homecoming?
聽著 我只想讓他想起大學有多棒
Look, I just wanna remind him how great college is.
讓他看看校園 看場比賽
Let him check out the campus, watch the big game,
還有不是剛滿十八歲的女孩兒
and we'll see some girls that didn't just turn 18.
你認為這就能讓他
And you think this is gonna make him
- 奇跡般地返校嗎  - 我是樂觀主義者
- wanna magically re-enroll? - Hey, I'm an optimist.
我會讓他趕上明晚的舞會的
I'll have him back in time for the big dance tomorrow night.
或者 要是事情順利的話 就是四年之后的舞會了
Or, if things go well, in four years.
你知道的 Mike 你不能就這樣
You know, Mike, you can't just come up
用些精密的計謀以此來達到
with some sort of elaborate ploy so that you
和孩子們交流的目的
can have a conversation with your child...
Mike 我得掛了 過隧道 聽不清
Mike, I gotta go. Tunnel. Can't hear you.
抱歉 愛你 再見
Sorry. Love you. Bye.
猜猜誰要過女生之夜啦
Guess who's having girl's night?
我討厭你這樣唱出來
I hate it when you sing stuff.
耶
Yeah.
你和我  哦 太抱歉了
Me and you... Oh, you know, I'm sorry.
天啊 我太愛開車了
Gosh, I love to drive.
你知道開車讓我想起什么嗎
You know what driving reminds me of?
- 大學  - 哦
- College. - Oh!
Reese剛把她舞會裙子的照片發給了我
Reese just texted me a picture of her homecoming dress.
- 她不知道這樣會有厄運嗎  - 我一生中最好的四年
- Doesn't she know that's bad luck? - Best four years of my life.
樹 湖 漂亮的花兒
Trees, lakes, beautiful flowers?
這不是新澤西 我們到底在哪兒
This isn't New Jersey. Where the hell are we?
肯定是轉錯彎了
Must have taken a wrong turn.
現在也到了北邊了 你知道咱該去哪兒看看嗎
Well, since we're upstate, you know what we should do?
去去康奈爾大學唄
We should go to Cornell.
我聽說他們弄了個
I hear they're having a
返校周末 都你這歲數的孩子
homecoming weekend for all the kids your age.
開玩笑呢吧 康奈爾離家有兩百多英里
Are you serious? Cornell's, like, 200 miles away from home.
晚禮服店  到了七點
And the tux shop... by 7:00,
那些好的手杖都被挑走啦
they'll have given away all the good canes!
- 那我就是幫你倆忙了  - 想不到你竟然綁架了我
- So I did you two favors. - I can't believe you kidnapped me.
這才不是綁架 現在不要抱怨了
It's not a kidnapping. Now stop complaining
不然我就切下你的耳朵寄回家給你媽
before I cut off your ear and send it home to your mom.
鎖上了 我控制著呢
It's locked. I control it.
我的計劃是讓
The plan was to get
Eve舒服到足以對我吐訴一切
Eve comfortable enough to open up to me about everything.
不僅是那個什么Jonah的事兒
Not just whoever this Jonah person was.
她得明白
She needs to understand
我不僅是她媽 我也是她的閨蜜
that I'm not just a mom. I'm one of the girls.
很有趣 是吧 還要點曲奇餅干糊不
This is fun, right? Do you want some more cookie dough?
- 來一管就夠了  - 好的 好的
- The first tube was enough. - Okay, all right.
那么 你最近有啥事沒有啊
So, any stuff going on with you?
男孩兒的事 或是普通的事
Any guy stuff or regular stuff?
- 任何事  - 沒什么 沒有
- Any... stuff? - Not really. No.
別這樣 我只是 我想
Oh, come on, I just... I wanna
- 知道個情況咯  - 什么
- know what the haps is. - Huh?
幾個情況 你幾個情況咯
Are, what the hap... haps... what the haps are.
這是個過程
It's a process.
你想干點什么 我們能互相編辮子
So what do you wanna do? We could braid each other's hairs.
我們能看看雜志
We could read some magazines.
看看雜志 當兩個雜志八婆
You know, we could read 'em and be a couple of mag hags.
- 行了 我不玩了  - 別 別 別
- Okay, I'm out. - No, no, no!
我不鬧了 抱歉
I'll stop, I'll stop. I'm sorry.
嗨 兄弟們
Hey, bros.
我要做個奶昔 我只需要你借我個攪拌機
Making myself a smoothie. All I need is your blender,
還有點草莓 杏仁奶油 希臘酸奶 亞麻
and some strawberries, almond butter, greek yogurt, flax,
一個熟透的香蕉和冰塊
an over ripe banana, ice.
- 袋子里是什么  - 我要洗的衣服呀 謝啦
- What's in the bags? - Oh, my laundry. Thanks.
嘿 Leigh姑姑 留下來待會兒吧
Hey, Aunt Leigh, you should stay and hang.
我們在過女生之夜呢
We're having a girls night.
你就是這么叫的 對吧 媽
That's what you called it, right, Mom?
是啊 我的確這么叫的
Uh, yeah, yeah, I d... yeah, I did call it that.
我的天啊 我一定要告訴你
Oh, my god, I have to tell you
那個誰關于那啥說了點什么 你懂的
what you-know-who said about you know what.
聽起來太有料了
Ooh! Oh, that sounds juicy!
女生之夜 就是要特別詳細
Girls night! It's all about being, you know, really specific.
棒極了 還是沒信號 Reese沒準以為我死了
Great. Still no signal. Reese probably thinks I'm dead.
- 或是以為你睡著了  - 不可能
- Or napping. - Not possible.
我把手機塞在腋下一震動就能醒
I tuck my phone in my armpit in case it vibrates.
這是個好想法 就跟個人體自帶口袋一樣
That's good thinking. It's like nature's pocket.
Reese一定會以為我放她鴿子
You know, Reese is gonna think I ditched her,
然后她就會和帥哥Kevin去舞會了
and then she's gonna go to the dance with hot Kevin.
他健身 他彈貝斯
Yeah, he works out. He plays the bass.
他最好的一點就是
And the best part about him is,
他根本不知道自己有多帥
he doesn't even know how hot he is.
你知道嗎 大學的好處就是
You know, the good thing about college is,
你在那兒可以嘗試 如果你
you can experiment there, if... you...
- 得了吧 爸爸  - 試著給你找找信號
- Aw, come on, Dad. - All right, let's try to get you a signal.
<Rhythm is a dancer>
Rhythm is a dancer!
<Rhythm is a dancer> Snap! 德國舞曲組合
難以置信你們竟然聽
Oh, wow, I can't believe you guys listened
- 這么俗氣的歌  - 俗氣
- to such cheesy music. - "Cheesy"?
這是最偉大的歌曲之一了
This is one of the greatest songs!
就像詩人Turbo B曾說過的"我就像癌癥一樣嚴肅"
And as the poet Turbo B says, "I'm serious as cancer."
Turbo B 曾為Snap!中成員 此句為他在<Rhythm is a dancer>中歌詞
掃一下 再掃一下 開始跳 砰 轉過來
And swipe it, and swipe it, and dance, pow, turn.
曳步舞 曳步舞 曳步舞
Running man, running man, running man,
- 曳步舞 曳步舞  - 蟲子舞
- running man, running man. - The worm!
蟲子舞 是的
The worm! That's right!
沒有錯 蟲子舞
Oh, yeah, it's the worm! It's the worm.
你看著 等著啊
Oh, you watch this. You just wait
看你媽媽跳的 就這樣
and see your mother. That's right.
- 厲害啊 媽  - 蟲子舞
- Nice, Mom. - The worm, the worm!
蟲子舞...
The worm... ooh, oh, god.
天 蟲子舞
Oh, god. The worm.
蟲子舞
The worm, the worm.
哦 老天爺
Oh, my god.
還是沒信號 也沒路標
Well, still no signal. Or road signs.
- 有沒有可能我們穿越回去了  - 我們只是有點迷路
- Is it possible we're in the past? - We're a little lost.
你媽有一年不是給我一個GPS做圣誕禮物嗎
I... didn't mom give me a GPS for Christmas one year?
沒準那年圣誕還沒到呢
Maybe that Christmas hasn't happened yet.
拜托 讓我開吧 這速度我們哪兒也到不了
Please, just let me drive. We're getting nowhere at this rate.
抱歉啦 是我藥的關系
I'm sorry, it's my meds.
時速超過四十五我就會感覺像是博爾特在開賽車
Going 45 makes me feel like Usain Bolt in a race car.
等我們回去的時候
You know, by the time we get back,
Reese都該高中畢業了
Reese will have graduated high school.
- 但愿如此  - 夠了 我要出去
- If only. - Okay, I'm getting out.
你不能從正在開的車里出去
You're not getting out of a moving car.
我能從這輛幾乎不動的車里出去
I can get out of a barely moving car.
- 你不能 什么  - 爸 看路 有頭鹿
- You're not... what... whoa. - Dad, watch out! Deer!
- 剎車啊  - 我在剎
- Brake! - I am!
我們改變了未來
We've changed the future.
- 它還有呼吸  - 謝天謝地
- It's still breathing. - Thank god.
- 那我們得殺了它  - 是啊
- So we should kill it. - Yeah.
- 什么 用什么 石頭嗎  - 它剛被車撞了
- What? With what, a rock? - It just got hit by a car.
你得讓它從痛苦中解脫出來
You have to put it out of its misery.
首先 我不能用石頭殺死動物
First of all, I can't kill an animal with a rock.
這得花上很長時間 這太殘忍了
It would take hours. It would be the worst kind of torture.
我知道你做不來
I didn't think you'd do it.
好 我準備好了
Okay, I'm good to go.
快放下
Put that down.
- 爸 它撐不下去的  - 你怎么知道
- Dad, it's not gonna make it. - You don't know that.
一只鹿倒下了 你就準備殺了它
A deer goes down, you're ready to kill it.
你掛了門經濟學 你就準備退學
You fail one econ class, you're ready to drop out of college.
- 你的適應力哪兒去了  - 你是怎么知道的
- Where's your resilience? - How did you know about that?
康奈爾給我寄了成績單
Cornell sent me a transcript.
這群笨蛋 他們為什么要這么做
Those idiots. Why would they do that?
因為我付了他們四萬刀
'Cause I pay them $40,000.
美國大學學費大多這個價
記下了 我到底還殺不殺這只鹿了
Noted. Am I killing the deer or not?
不行 這只鹿是個戰士
Not. This deer is a fighter.
如果你像我一樣有積極的態度
If you had a positive attitude like me,
你看著它 就會看到它...跑了
you'd look at it and you'd see that it's... gone.
- 鹿到哪兒去了  - 一定是一瘸一拐的跑了
- Where did the deer go? - Must have limped off.
我要把它追回來
I'm gonna go chase him down.
別 它說不定和同伴一起走了 正告訴它們
No, he's probably off with the fellas, telling 'em
那個熊孩子打算拿石頭砸死它的事兒呢
about this crazy kid that tried to kill him with a rock.
Ian 別那么固執 跟個孩子似的
Ian, don't be stubborn. Don't be such a child.
媽呀
Mama!
當時Giancarlo欲火焚身 他特想要我
So Giancarlo was torn. He really wanted me.
但是他也想吃培根芝士漢堡
But he also wanted a bacon cheeseburger.
幸運的是 得來速的隊伍排的老長
Luckily... there was a long line at the drive-through.
哦 老天 你們竟然在得來速車道上做愛了
Oh, my god. You had sex at a drive-through?
是啊 聽起來蠻爽的 就像字面意思一樣
I know! It sounds sexy, but by definition, you have to be done
你得在美國芝士融化之前完事兒
in the time it takes to melt American cheese.
一整晚上 我都在跟Leigh比誰更酷一些
All night long, I was competing to be as cool as Leigh,
但我發現 人們對她敞開心扉 是因為她也特敞
but then I realized, people open up to her because she's so open.
哦 老天 真是太搞笑了
Oh, my god. That is hilarious.
好吧 可不是只有Leigh有故事哦
Okay, Leigh's not the only one with some stories.
我可要警告一下你 我要說的可是限制級的
And let me warn you, this one is a little R-rated.
看見那塊兒的燙傷沒
You see that burn right there?
摩托車消音器燙的
That's from a muffler.
事實上 我都不知道自己的腿能彎成那樣
The thing is, I didn't even know my legs could bend like that.
但是當你在摩托車上做愛時
But when you are doing it on a motorcycle,
- 總會想出法子 - 這可能嗎
- you make it work. - Is that even possible?
當然 我去拿Graham的娃娃擺給你看
Oh, yeah, let me show you on some of Graham's toys.
- 好的 不用試了 - 等下
- Okay, hey, we're all set. - Hold on.
如果那時是大學時期 天 是跟老爸嗎
If that was in college... oh, god. Was that Dad?
不 不 不是跟你爸爸
No! No, it wasn't your father.
- 那就是跟別人了 惡心 - 不是 是跟你爸爸
- So it was someone else? Ew! - No, it... it was your father...
- 惡心 - 我 抱歉 天哪
- Ew! - I ... I'm sorry. God.
我都跟你說了好幾個小時了
I've been telling you for hours,
我從大學里退學不是因為我掛科
I didn't drop out of college because of one failed class.
是掛科讓我懷疑我為什么還要上大學
The class made me question why I was even in college.
我想要做自己想做的事情
I wanted to do my own thing.
你想做的事兒就是扔樹葉嗎
Is that your thing, throwing leaves?
我是在看風朝哪邊吹
I'm seeing which way the wind is blowing.
我們要順風接近那頭鹿
We want to approach the deer from downwind.
我可是雄鷹童子軍 看來
Eagle scout. Guess you can
鷹軍是美國童子軍最高榮譽
從大學以外的地方也能學習到東西
learn things in places that aren't college.
掛科了的孩子都會覺得自己不適合上大學
Every kid who fails a class thinks college isn't for them.
我知道什么是逆境
I know something about adversity.
你需要用樂觀的精神面對它
You just gotta face it with optimism.
聽我說 老爸 你對鹿樂觀
Look, Dad, you're optimistic about this deer.
你也對自己的身體狀況樂觀
You're optimistic about your health.
你對這世界上除了我的所有事情都樂觀
You're optimistic about everything in this world but me.
- 當然不是了 - 聽著 你得了帕金森癥很糟
- That's not true. - Look, it sucks that you got Parkinson's.
但是你很好的面對了它
And it's great the way you've handled it,
但是你經歷那些勵志旅程時
but this whole inspiring journey that you went on,
我還小啊
that was my childhood.
對我來說既害怕又難熬
And it was scary and it was hard.
我只是想讓你知道 我已經在盡力做到最好了
I just want you to know that I'm... I'm trying to do my best.
我真的希望你能看到
And I wish you could see that.
我很抱歉 Ian我真沒意識到
I'm... I'm sorry, Ian, I had no idea...
不 我們一直在繞圈
No, we're going around in circles!
是的 但是我們把話說清楚更重要
Yeah, but it's important we get this out.
不 我們就見過這個爛樹根了
No, we passed by this rotten log before.
為什么它老跟著我
Why is it after me?
可能是它覺得能把你抓走
Probably because he thinks he can carry you off.
好吧 我知道你現在需要點私人空間
Okay, I know you need your personal space right now,
但我只能給你十英尺
but I'm just giving you ten feet.
嗨 老媽 你干嘛睡地板上
Oh, hey, Mom. What are you doing on the floor?
你懂的 睡眠派對
Oh, you know, it's a slumber party.
你晚上睡得晚了就得睡在
You stay up late and sleep on
地板上矯正一下你的脊椎
the floor so you can stabilize your vertebrae.
- 你要去哪啊 寶貝 - 那啥 你知道的
- Were you leaving, honey? - Well, you know how it is.
- 我還是喜歡睡我自己的床 - 好的 我玩的挺愉快的
- I sleep better in my own bed. - All right, well... I had fun.
是啊 是啊 我也是
Yeah. Yeah, me too.
- 晚會兒見 - 好的
- I'll see you when I see you. - Yeah.
這一夜情溜出門可真堅決啊
Wow. That was a pretty solid one night stand sneak-out.
這妞兒將來會傷不少人的心
That girl's gonna break a lot
還能避免不少尷尬的早午餐
of hearts and avoid a lot of awkward brunches.
唉 昨晚真是糟透了
Ugh, last night was a disaster.
是啊 你當時什么計劃啊
Yeah, what was the plan there?
我不知道
I don't know!
我只是想讓Eve跟我談談心就像跟你談心一樣
I just wanted Eve to open up to me like she opens up to you.
親愛的 這事兒你就別想了
Sweetie... that's never gonna happen.
- Eve是青少年 - 我知道
- Eve's a teenager. - I know.
你哪怕是世界上最酷的人
You could be the coolest person in the world,
但是對她來說 你永遠都是老媽
but to her, you'll always be her mother.
她不想和你談論她的生活
She doesn't want to talk about her life with you.
老媽很遜 科學就是這樣表明的
Moms are lame. It's just science.
哦 你醒了啊
Oh. You're awake.
你說過不用的東西就可以不要了
You said we don't keep things we don't use.
Graham 這些東西很貴的 你還拿了什么東西
Graham, this stuff is valuable. What else did you take?
你不記得了嗎
Don't you remember?
150塊錢的"激勵"牛仔褲 只是小了兩個碼
$150 aspirational jeans. They're two sizes too small
果汁減肥法后我就能穿上它了
because I was gonna fit into them after my juice cleanse.
好吧 都弄走
All right, take it away.
我以為我們都回不來了
I thought we'd never get back,
- 但是你做到了 - 妥妥的
- but you did it. - Of course I did.
要不是你擔心那雙意大利皮鞋
If you hadn't been so worried about your Italian shoes,
就不會花這么久了
you would have made better time.
是啊 另一只鞋子給貓頭鷹搶去做壓寨夫人了
Yeah, one of those shoes is now married to an owl.
別這樣 Ian 你已經好幾個小時不理我了
Come on, Ian, you've been freezing me out for hours.
- 我們能不能 - 我收到信號了
- Can we just... - Oh! I got signal!
兩格
Two bars!
喂 Reese 是我 我很好
Hello, Reese? It's me! Oh! I'm fine.
我整個晚上都試著給你打電話 只是我
I've been trying to call you all night. It's just that I...
喂 不 不 一秒前還有兩格信號的
Hello? What... No! No, I had two bars a second ago!
信號哪去了
Where did the signal go?
要是能找到個地勢高點的地方
Oh, if I just can get to a higher ground,
我說不定就能收到點信號
I'll be able to get a clearer path to the transmitter.
我就能
I could get...
他沒有放棄
He doesn't give up.
人造革
Oh! Synthetic.
好的 B計劃 你有什么銀的物件嗎
Okay, plan B. Do you have any silver fillings?
你比我想象中堅強的多
You know, you're a lot tougher than I realized.
也許我沒有顧忌到你小時候的心情
Maybe I didn't notice what you went through as a kid
是因為你一直都處理的很好
because you handled it so well.
其實也沒什么大不了的
Yeah, the... you know, it's not that big deal.
我倒是因為這個獲得不少同情親熱
I got a lot of sympathy make outs because of it.
好吧 關于大學的事兒我不再提了
Well, I won't bother you about college anymore.
你可以自己做主了
You're your own man.
現在就送你去高中舞會
Now let's get you to the high school dance.
- 好的 但是我來開車 - 嗯 好的
- Okay, but I'm driving. - Yeah, okay.
- 這兒 接著 - 啊
- Here. Head's up. - Ugh.
好吧 這下可好了
Okay... that's great.
不管你如何努力反抗 終究會走到一個截點
No matter how hard you try to fight it, you reach a point
一個你不能再強迫你孩子照你意愿行事的截點
with your kids where you can't force 'em to do what you want.
好吧 你能留一件
Okay, you can keep one,
但是你必須答應我你會玩它
but you have to promise me you'll play with it.
我保證
I promise.
你拿了手杖
You got the cane!
跟Eve在一起那個男的是誰
Who is that guy eve’s with.
我都跟你說過了 Mike 這種事情你就別操心了
I told you Mike, we've gotta just relax about these things.
你覺得陪護人能跳舞嗎
Do you think chaperones are allowed to dance?
當然 我要是動的太少別嫌棄我
Yeah, just don't be offended if I don't move much.
要是我動的太多別嫌棄我
Don't be offended if I do.
事實上 他們終會出落的十分出眾
In fact, they could turn out pretty spectacular.
哦 我們兒子火了
Oh, our son is on fire!
- 是 他跳舞可好了呢 - 不是 親愛的
- Yeah, he's a good dancer. - No, honey, he's...
- 他是真的著火了 - 救命
- he's actually on fire. - Help!
Ian
Ian!
而總有一天 他們會尋路回到你身邊
And eventually, they'll find a way back to you.
Eve 怎么了
Eve, what's wrong?
告訴我到底怎么了 好吧
Do you wanna tell me what happened? Okay, okay.
但是說不定只有我這么想
But maybe that's just me.
我是個樂觀主義者
I'm an optimist.
值了
Worth it.
電波字幕組 歡迎您的加入
官方網站:www.dbfansub.com
新浪微博:@電波字幕組